<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wordpress | Linux Sysadmin Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://linuxsysadminblog.com/category/wordpress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://linuxsysadminblog.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T23:19:31+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://linuxsysadminblog.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Promet OPS Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress 3 Error: Briefly unavailable for scheduled maintenance. Check back in a minute.]]></title>
    <link href="http://linuxsysadminblog.com/2010/10/wordpress-3-error-briefly-unavailable-for-scheduled-maintenance/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-16T18:51:31+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://linuxsysadminblog.com/2010/10/wordpress-3-error-briefly-unavailable-for-scheduled-maintenance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You'll get this error when Wordpress automatic update process, via svn or admin, fail or is incomplete.  It leaves the file named "<em>.maintenance</em>" on your home or root directory, with info on maintenance.</p>

<p>Sample content of .maintenance file: <code>&lt;?php $upgrading = 1282258195; ?&gt;</code></p>

<p>Just delete or rename that file and resume your update process, or you may want to restore your backup first and re-start the update process.  Of course, check what cause the failed or incomplete update. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hidden Wordpress Spam: ]]></title>
    <link href="http://linuxsysadminblog.com/2009/05/hidden-wordpress-spam/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-22T00:38:39+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://linuxsysadminblog.com/2009/05/hidden-wordpress-spam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A month ago one of our customers complained on lots of spam comments appearing on his <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> site.  There's no development changes, including updates, to that site since it was launched and it runs on WP version 2.3.3.  We managed the issue by activating the <a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/Akismet">Akismet</a> plugin and upgrading the Wordpress to latest version (2.7.1 at this time).</p>

<p><img src="http://linuxsysadminblog.com/images/2009/05/mh-300x185.jpg" alt="reference" /></p>

<p>Yesterday, the same customer reported back the spam results appearing on Google search from his site.  So i checked all the approved comments and pages on the site but i found nothing.   At first I thought it was on Google cache but i don't think it's the case since it's been a month since we implemented the spam filter and wp upgrade.  Then I checked on the database contents and found several spam messages inserted on blog posts, most of them were inserted at the end of posts.</p>

<p>Spam messages looks like this:
```</p>

<!-- manager-start -->


<p>  <style>div.ONqjGUvTIf {height: 0pt;width: 3pt;position: absolute;overflow: auto}</style><div class="ONqjGUvTIf">viagra anxiety  <a href="http://insiteblog.mit.edu/?item=201&desc;=generic-brands-of-viagra-online"> generic brands of viagra online</a> taking viagra woman\ncheap gerneric viagra <a href="http://insiteblog.mit.edu/?item=33&desc;=viagra-dosage">viagra dosage</a> "generic  </div></p>

<!-- manager-end -->


<p>```</p>

<p>If you check on the blog pages you can't see these text so you can't easily tell that the posts/pages were attacked, but if you try to view the html source generated by the browser you can see them - that is why it is included when Google index/crawl your site contents or pages.  These spam appeared to have been inserted before our WP upgrade to it must be an exploit on our old WP version (2.3.3).</p>

<p>To remove you can edit the post from your WP Admin section or you can edit directly from database (ex: phpmyadmin).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
